# TRAVIS NELSON

SOFTWARE CRAFTSMAN / FULL-STACK DEVELOPER / CONSULTANT

# PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

12+ years experience in server and client-side development. Certified Google Analytics, Certified ScrumMaster, Certified Umbraco Developer Level I and Level II, Stanford University Software Security Foundations certificate, contribution to several patent filings and awards, complete web application development from proposal through project delivery, maintenance, and marketing.

Areas of expertise: Web development, C#, .NET, SQL, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Umbraco, .NET MVC, ASP. NET Web API, Microsoft Azure, Git.

# SOCIAL

- stackoverflow.travis.io
- witter.travis.io
- in linkedin.travis.io
- github.travis.io

# CONTACT

#### **Address**

280 Jeanette St. Canton, GA 30114

#### **Email**

me@travis.io

### Mobile/SMS

941-276-0763

## Skype

trnelson

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 2009 - 2016

### Scientific Games (formerly Williams Interactive, WMS Gaming)

Principal Software Engineer II

Full-stack development, .NET, CQRS, SQL Server, Web API, JavaScript, jQuery, Agile. Site and server administration in Windows Azure. SCM migration and administration (GitHub Enterprise, Visual SVN), patents, process improvements within the organization. Previously: ASP.NET, WCF, Umbraco, HTML, CSS, design.

#### 2013 - Present

#### **Consulting and Contract Development**

Paradigm Productions, Senior Umbraco Consultant

- Umbraco, .NET, feature development, content management Alii Healthcare, *Senior Development Consultant*
- Web API, .NET MVC, PostgreSQL, Angular.js, HTML, CSS General Assembly, *Instructor, Part Time*
- Front-End Web Development (FEWD), part-time instructor ThreadKM, Senior Development Consultant
- · Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular.js, Ruby, HTML, CSS

#### 2007-2009

#### **Marketing Max**

Creative Director and Lead Developer

Design and development for clients including Terminix, TruGreen, Sage Software, and ComputerJobs.com. Managed projects from consultation through design, launch, maintenance, and marketing. Development in ASP.NET using C# and SQL Server, and integration with third-party APIs and tools including Google Maps, Authorize.Net, and PayPal.

#### 2006-2007

#### Selina Naturally (formerly The Grain & Salt Society)

Website / Systems Administrator

Management and maintenance of information systems including website, computers, network, servers, phone network. Development of website features. Design and programming support for marketing team, email campaigns, list management, and web promotions.

#### SKILLS

.NET (C#) HTML/CSS JavaScript .NET Web API SQL Server Git/SVN

_		

SOLID
Design Patterns
Agile
Architecture
Graphic Design
Marketing



# TRAVIS NELSON

SOFTWARE CRAFTSMAN / FULL-STACK DEVELOPER / CONSULTANT

# PERSONAL INTERESTS

Graphic Design
Branding
Writing
Marketing
Business
Data/Analytics
Muay Thai
Strength Training
Instruction
Mentorship

# CONTACT

INFORMATION

#### Address

280 Jeanette St. Canton, GA 30114

#### **Email**

me@travis.io

### Mobile/SMS

941-276-0763

## Skype

trnelson

#### **EDUCATION**

Ongoing Computer Science

Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw, GA

4.0 GPA, courses include: Statistics, Algebra, Calculus, Macroeconomics,

Microeconomics, English Composition II – Technical Writing, Psychology, Ethics, Speech Communications - Public Speaking.

1999 - 2002 Advanced Diploma - Multimedia Production

Confederation College of Applied Arts and Technology, Thunder Bay, ON

3.74 GPA, Dean's List graduate of the three-year Multimedia Production program at Confederation College, including successful completion of a four month, 576-hour internship.

## INTERESTS AND AREAS OF STUDY

SOLID design, design patterns, test-driven development and mocking, continuous integration, Agile and Kanban, cloud development (Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Rackspace Cloud), software architecture (services-oriented, architecture, REST, domain-driven design, caching, table/blob/queue), mobile, single page applications (Angular,js), UI design (Bootstrap, jQuery, LESS, SASS), analytics, marketing, user experience, security, API design, best practices, alternate frameworks (Node,js, React,js, Python, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Redis).